AKSHAY G

Front-End Developer | JavaScript | React JS | Html | Css

+91 8754070533

mailto.akshay.dev@gmail.com

Gummidipoondi, Chennai

SUMMARY

Persevering learner and diligent team player with 2 years of experience specializing in UI development using the React library. Skilled software engineer with expertise in AI-powered recruiting applications, HRMS, ticket management, educational timeline systems, and ERP applications. You can view my portfolio here.

SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, React.Js, Bootstrap, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router,

Git, GitHub, Bit bucket, Rest, Axios, Fetch, Scss, Firebase, i18n-js, Jitsi, validate.js,

React-player, React-photo-view, React-DND, React-Select

EXPERIENCE

React JS Developer - 06/2022 - Present

Leora Infotech Private Limited - Gummidipoondi, Chennai.

- Responsible for frontend design and development
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning
- Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

Payment Assistance - 30/09/2021 - 14/03/2022

MATRIMONY.COM LIMITED - Guindy, Chennai.

• Utilizing chat and system calls, I addressed user concerns, convinced them of

package benefits, and ensured a smooth transaction experience.

Data Provisioning Executive - 01/2019 - 11/2019

Tenth Planet Technologies - Mount Road, Chennai.

• Provide customized enterprise IT solutions, centered around open source software, troubleshoot issues, and ensure compliance.

Process Associate - 04/2017 - 11/2017

String Information Services - Saidapet, Chennai.

• Mortgage Process Outsourcing (MPO) - tailored solutions, optimize and streamline mortgage processes, enhance efficiency, reduce costs.

PROJECTS

INTRVU SPACE — Hiring Application (AI) | Link

• intrvu SPACE helps you conduct automated Interviews, Generate Reports, and Approve Candidates end to end with zero manual effort.

Contribution: Landing page, Login, OTP, Corporate flow, CRUD candidate flow, Settings, Job seeker flow, Report

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

Zeny Q — HRMS | Link

 Employee management application with features like attendance and payroll management.

Contribution: Api integration and data normalization, Salary slip.

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, push notification.

Quanta TMS — Ticket Management Solution

• Enhances task and ticket management for improved collaboration.

Contribution: Login, OTP, Individual & Group chats, Task, Ticket, Association, Feeds, Event

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification.

Quanta EDAT — EduTech Application

• Offers comprehensive programming courses with practical tasks and mock interviews.

Contribution: Course CRUD, Tasks, Topics, Schedule Interview, Online Sessions **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js.

NS Instruments - FG — Finished Goods Management

• Optimises inventory control with streamlined stock and product management.

Contribution: Login, OTP, Dispatch request, Stock request and Paginated Listing **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification.

EDUCATION

Bsc Computer Science - 2013 - 2016 Shree Chandraprabhu Jain College Minjur, Chennai.

XII (HSS) - 2011 -2013

St.Marys Matric Hr Sec Chinthala Kuppam, Gummidipoondi.

X (SSLC) - 2010 - 2011

Shanthiniketan Matric Hr Sec New Gummidipoondi.

LANGUAGES

Tamil: Mother Tongue English: Professional (Conversationally fluent)

Malayalam: Conversationally fluent Hindi: Writing and Reading